<rss version="2.0">
 <channel>
   <title>gablaxy's website</title>
   <link>https://gablaxy.github.io/soper/articles/</link>
   <description>Good website</description>
   <item>
    <title>framework 2eme volume</title>
     <link>https://gablaxy.github.io/soper/articles/framework%202eme%20volume</link>
     <description>
                <![CDATA[

                First update on my situation,
            </p>
            <p>
                I'm happy to say that I no longer live in a moldy flat in the city center but near my uni in a brand new building made for students.
                The flat is really nice and the only downside is that I don't know what the architect was thinking when designing the interior because the placement of the outlets makes no sense...
                Otherwise I love it here, I love that I now have a big window that brings in a lot of light, my plants are gonna love it !!!
            </p>
            <p>
                Onto the topic of this article, I got my framework during the winter holidays, I bought the AMD DIY version without any ram or storage.
                I ordered instantly those two things because I couldn't wait anymore to build it ! 
            </p>
            <p>
                As advertised it was so easy to install anything, it brought me so much joy. 
                I also discovered some details like the facts that the replacement screws have a place directly in the laptop and not in a plastic bag that I would have lost in no time.
            </p>
            <p>
                I installed manjaro with gnome as a desktop environment for now, I will see how that goes, maybe I will change but I don't know. I pondered for some time between this and debian but as I saw that the official support for framework was primarely Ubuntu and Manjaro, I chose the one that for me is less profit oriented.
            </p>
            <p>
                For now I really like it, i was thinking that the battery would be atrocious but it is not that bad and the only problem I encountered was that the right click on the touch pad isn't working but as I always use and external mouse I didn't even took it apart to check if a the cable is maybe not fully connected.
            </p>
            <p>
                I will probably make another post in a few month to a year to give a review when the laptop has more mileage.
            </p>
            <p>Thanks for reading me.</p>
                ]]>
  
</description>
     <pubDate>January 8, 2025</pubDate>
   </item>
    <item>
     <title>framework</title>
     <link>https://gablaxy.github.io/soper/articles/framework</link>
     <description>
     
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>
                        Hello again,
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        Today I'm writing from my moldy student flat. I have been thinking about relocating to a university dorm as there are some new ones that just opened this September. I just don't know if they have any spaces left.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        Just thinking about the papers and all the administration-related things that I'm gonna have to do to move less than two kilometers is making my brain hurt a little. But university dorms are less expensive in my country (and every other country I think...), probably less moldy, and they have better insulation. As winter is starting, I don't want to freeze to death because my radiator is currently heating the outside more than the inside, rofl.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        That being said, the main topic of this article was to talk about the Framework laptop. I am currently pondering if I should buy one because the only laptop I have now is a "gaming one" that is really heavy and has no battery life. It is now 3.5 years old, and with how electronic devices' life expectancy is always getting worse and worse somehow, I don't want to find myself without any computer during my now starting (I mean it's been already 3 months but whatever) first year of master.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        So back to our topic, I already knew about framework but it was a bit too expensive for me, know it's within my budget (even if it's still a bit expensive) and it really align well with my view, I want the most sustainable laptop possible and a laptop that comes with no pre-installed OS so I can do what I want with it.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        I love their iniative and I hope that it inspire a lot of other people to do similar things in tech or just in everyday utilities.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        However I still have one problem, thanks to the type of credit card I have, my maximum withdrawal amount is near the price of the laptop I want lol (DIY framework 13, with pretty much the cheapest options). I have thinked about different way to solve this problem (so that I doesn't end up without being able to buy anything else, like food or rent rofl, for the rest of the month), their website doesn't allow paypal or multiple time payement, and I think I may be able to buy it near the end of the year or the start of 2025.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        Thanks for reading my mess of an article and see yoou next time.
                    </p>
                ]]>
  
</description>
     <pubDate>November 24, 2024</pubDate>
   </item>
   <item>
     <title>The talk</title>
     <link>https://gablaxy.github.io/soper/articles/future_space</link>
     <description>I started outlining the different topics i will talk about on this blog, like space and tech "news", sci-fi/fantasy writings of my own maybe. 
     For the tech things, i think it will be mostly about open source because that's what i like the most in computer science.
     I also want to make some place on this website to keep track of the ideas i get, so that they don't disappear when i throw the piece of paper i wrote them on without thinking.
     I may add a tag system on this blog if it starts to scale up a bit...</description>
     <pubDate>October 10, 2024</pubDate>
   </item>
   <item>
     <title>First blog post</title>
     <link>https://gablaxy.github.io/soper/articles/hello%20world</link>
     <description>First blog post, I think i will try to relocate the website as soon as possible to be independant totally, at the same time i will try to add more content on this website, for example blog posts, books to read, a showcase of my projects and other things. </description>
     <pubDate>June 8, 2023</pubDate>
   </item>
 </channel>
</rss> 
